stryker.com 2017-06-29

# Stryker - Medical Devices & Equipment Manufacturing Company : Stryker

**Privacy Statement**

**PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT CAREFULLY**

Your privacy is very important to Stryker. We also understand that privacy is very important to you. This Privacy Statement ("Privacy Statement") is designed to tell you about our practices regarding collection, use and disclosure of any information we gather through this web site located at stryker.com and other Stryker web sites. This web site is owned and operated by Stryker Corporation. Stryker Corporation and its affiliates (hereafter referred to as "Stryker") also operate other web sites. This Privacy Statement may also apply to those other web sites. Please review the privacy statement posted on those other Stryker web sites when you visit them.

Stryker reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement at any time and for any reason. The last date this Statement was modified can be found at the end of the Statement. We encourage you to look at this Privacy Statement each time you visit the site and especially before you provide any personally identifiable information.

By using this site you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Please read the entire Privacy Statement and our [_Terms of Use_](http://www.stryker.com/en-us/TERMS_OF_USE) before using or submitting information to any Stryker web site. Except as written in any other disclaimers, policies, user agreements, terms of use or other notices, this Privacy Statement and the [_Terms of Use_](http://www.stryker.com/en-us/TERMS_OF_USE) are the complete agreement between you and Stryker with respect to your use of this site. You may be subject to additional terms that may apply when you access particular services or materials on certain areas of this site or by following links that take you away from this site. 

**INTRODUCTION**

The information we receive and how we use it depends on what you do when visiting our site. We collect and use your non-personal information (information that is not identifiable to you personally) differently than your personal information. 

**WHAT IS NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION? **

Each time you visit this site to read or download information we may collect certain information about you from your computer. This information is collected from your computer's web browser and may include information such as the following ("non-personal information"): 

• The type of web browser software you use (for example: Firefox, Internet Explorer, etc.)

• The name of the domain from which you access the internet

• The internet address of the web site from which you linked directly to our site

• The date and time you access our site

• The pages you have visited on our site

• Information that has been de-identified 

If you only read or download information on our site, we do not collect or learn your name, email address, home address or other personal information about you; however, certain non-personal or anonymous information may be passively collected (that is gathered without your actively providing the information) using various technologies, such as cookies, internet tags or web beacons and navigational data collection (log files, server logs, clickstream, etc.). Your internet browser automatically transmits to this site some of this anonymous information such as the URL of the web site you just came from and the internet protocol (IP) address and the browser version your computer is currently using. We may also place a text file called a cookie in the browser files of your computer when you visit. The cookie may be stored on your computer's hard drive. The information that we collect using cookies is non-personal information. U.S. Government Information Bulletin (I-034) contains a good description of cookie technology at: [_http://www.ciac.org/ciac/bulletins/i-034.shtml_](http://www.ciac.org/ciac/bulletins/i-034.shtml). You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits but some parts of our site may not work properly for you if you do so. We will not allow third parties to place cookies on our site. 

**WHAT DOES STRYKER DO WITH NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION? **

There are no restrictions to the way Stryker can use or share non-personal information. We will use non-personal information to help us make our site more useful to visitors and for other business purposes. We may prepare reports and other materials using non-personal information. Since these reports and materials contain no personal information, we may share them with others. All information that is not personal to you or someone else, such as questions, comments, and suggestions (collectively "feedback") shall be deemed to be non-confidential, and Stryker shall be free to disclose and use the same, for any purpose and through any means, without any obligation whatsoever to you. By choosing to send a message to Stryker, you acknowledge that all feedback will be considered to be non-confidential. Stryker shall have no obligations of any kind with respect to such feedback and shall be free to reproduce, use, disclose, exhibit, display, transform, commercialize, create derivative works and distribute the feedback to others without limitation. 

Further, Stryker shall have no obligation to acknowledge and may not be prohibited from using any ideas, inventions, concepts, know-how or techniques contained in such feedback or anything else you send to Stryker via the web site for any purpose whatsoever including but not limited to developing, manufacturing and marketing products incorporating such feedback. 

**WHAT IS PERSONAL INFORMATION? **

In some places on this site you may have the chance to send us information about yourself. For example, our site may include a registration form, surveys or email forms. Most of our services do not require any form of registration, allowing you to visit our site without telling us who you are. However, some services may require registration. When you register with us, you may need to complete certain fields (some are required and some are optional) as well as choose a user name and password. In these situations if you choose to withhold any personal data requested by us it may not be possible for you to gain access to certain parts of the site and for us to respond to you. The personal information that we collect if you fill out such forms or surveys, or when you ask us to personalize your visits to our site, may include for example: 

• Your name

• Address

• Email address

• Other personal information

**HOW DOES STRYKER USE PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

Stryker may use personal information we collect to do the following, including but not limited to: 

• Respond to your requests

• Contact you, via email, regular mail, telephone or otherwise 

• Provide you with information that we believe may be of interest to you

• Develop records, including records of your personal information

• Develop and improve programs, products, services and content

• Enforce this Privacy Statement and our [_Terms of Use_](http://www.stryker.com/en-us/TERMS_OF_USE) and other rules about your use of this site

• To protect Stryker's rights or property

• To protect someone's health, safety or welfare

• To comply with a law or regulation, court order or other legal process.

By submitting personal information (such as your name, address, email address or telephone number), you agree that we may keep a record of it and may use it in accordance with the above. We also may use your personal information to help us in our business, including but not limited to improving our site, marketing and/or product development.

**SHARING PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH OTHERS**

Stryker may transfer your personal information to the subsidiaries, divisions or other entities under common ownership with Stryker that agree to treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy and use it for the same purposes. You also agree that Stryker may share your personal information with third parties, but only:

• To contractors we use to support our business (such as fulfillment services, technical support, delivery services, and financial institutions), in which case we will require such third parties to agree to treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy and use it for the same purposes

• In connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of the business of this site to which the information relates, in which case we will require any such buyer to agree to treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy and use it for the same purposes

• To respond to law enforcement requests or where required by applicable laws, court orders, or government regulations.

These companies and/or individuals may not further use or share your personal information with others without our permission and only for the purpose of assisting us with our business activities pursuant to our request. Stryker will not sell, exchange or publish your personal information without your permission, except in conjunction with a corporate sale, merger, dissolution, acquisition or other similar event.

The collection, use and disclosure of information contemplated in this Privacy Policy may involve a transfer of the information to jurisdictions located outside your country of residence that may not have equivalent laws and rules regarding personally identifiable information. In these cases, you may be asked to consent to such transfers and disclosures in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

You agree that we may use your personal information to mail or email information to you about Stryker and our products and services.

**IS STRYKER EVER REQUIRED TO SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES?**

Except as otherwise written in this Privacy Statement, we will keep your personal information private and will not share it with others, unless the disclosure is necessary to: 

• Comply with a law or regulation, court order, subpoena or other legal process

• Protect our rights or property

• Enforce this Privacy Statement or our [_Terms of Use_](http://www.stryker.com/en-us/TERMS_OF_USE)

• Protect someone's health or safety.

In addition, you are prohibited from posting or transmitting any unlawful, threatening, libelous, defamatory, obscene, scandalous, inflammatory, pornographic or profane material or any material that could constitute or encourage conduct that would be considered a criminal offense, give rise to civil liability or otherwise violate any law. We will fully cooperate with any law enforcement authorities or court order requesting or directing us to disclose the identity of anyone posting any such information or materials.

**PATIENT INFORMATION**

If you provide us with data about other individuals, such as personal health information (PHI) or other personal information, please ensure that the individual or the individual’s personal representative is aware of the disclosure and that he or she consents to the disclosure as well as to our Privacy Policy, [_Terms of Use_](http://www.stryker.com/en-us/TERMS_OF_USE) and <Data Protection Statement> (if applicable).

**ACCESS, CORRECTION, AND DELETION**

To keep personally identifiable information that you provide via this site accurate, current and complete, please contact us at the address specified below and we will take appropriate steps to update or correct such information in our possession, or to delete your information from our contact list.

**SECURITY**

This site takes reasonable steps to protect personally identifiable information as you transmit it to our site and to protect such information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. You should keep in mind that no internet transmission is ever completely secure or error-free. In particular, email sent to or from this site may not be secure.

**WHAT ABOUT PRIVACY ON OTHER SITES?**

This site may contain links to other non-Stryker web sites to which this Privacy Statement does not apply. We provide these links for your convenience, but we do not review, control, or monitor the privacy practices of web sites operated by others. Stryker is not responsible for the performance of these sites or for your business dealings with them. Your use of any other web sites is subject to the terms and conditions of those sites, including the privacy policies of those sites.

**ARE THERE SPECIAL RULES ABOUT CHILDREN’S PRIVACY?**

We care about protecting the online privacy of children. This site is not intentionally designed for or directed at children 13 years of age or younger without obtaining prior consent from a person with parental responsibility. It is our policy to never knowingly collect or maintain information about anyone under the age of 13 (such as a child's name or email address). If you think that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, please contact us.

**HOW TO CONTACT US**

If you have any questions, comments, requests, or concerns related to this Privacy Statement or the information practices of this site, or if you would like to opt out of future communications, please contact us as follows:

Stryker Corporation

c/o: Corporate Compliance Officer

2825 Airview Boulevard

Kalamazoo, MI 49002

U.S.A.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

If this Privacy Statement changes, the revised policy will be posted on this site. Please check back periodically, and especially before you provide any personally identifiable information. This Privacy Statement was last updated on May 21, 2010.
